Kenan Bölükbası

Keran Davidov

Software Engineer, Game Developer & Designer, Architect

İSTANBUL - TURKEY KENANBOLUKBASI@GMAIL.COM 0 ☑ KENANB.COM ☑ 6x13.COM Windows: Itch.io: 🖵 ₽ **▼** KENANBOLUKBASI C KENANB C 6x13

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Software Engineer with in-depth knowledge in 3D scene description, surface representation and processing. Highly experienced in compiled languages, and low-level debugging. Highly experienced in project pipeline and tools development. Experienced in project management.

Previously: Game developer, and designer, Blender 3D specialist, Blender Foundation Certified Trainer.

PERSONAL DETAILS

CITIZENSHIP EU (Bulgarian), Turkish

DRIVER'S LICENCE B Class

EDUCATION

2005 - 2017 Architecture (B.Arch.)

Istanbul Technical University, ITU School of

Architecture, İstanbul

2001 - 2005High School (Science and Math)

Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School,

Bursa

HIGHLIGHTS

FILM CREDITS

2019 Avengers: Endgame

Weta Digital - Technology and Research

Conference Talks & Workshops

Prototyping & Optimizing Game Asset Workflow 2014 Blender Conference, Amsterdam

2014 Automated Sprite Rendering System in Blender Libre Graphics Meeting, Leipzig

Blender Python Programming Workshop 2014 BlendFX Studios, Leipzig

COMMUNICATION SKILLS

ENGLISH

- C2 (Mastery)*
- Prep Class Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School Technical English Course - ITU Academic Essay Writing Course – ITU Research Paper Writing Course - ITU
- Lives and works in Wellington, New Zealand since 2018. Previously, VIP event supervision in various countries.

TURKISH

- · Native Speaker
- (*) Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

WORK EXPERIENCE

UNITY Software Engineer MAR 2022 - [CONT'D]

WELLINGTON

Software Engineer at Weta Digital - Pipeline Department.

WETA DIGITAL | WĒTĀ FX

JAN 2018 - MAR 2022

Software Engineer

WELLINGTON

Software Engineer at Pipeline Department.

- · Development and integration of various technologies for visual effects pipelines.
- Development of visual effects artist focused tools, developer focused tools and software libraries.

6x13 GAMES

JAN 2015 - DEC 2017

Founder, Project Leader & Developer

İSTANBUL

Project leader. Game design and development. Graphic design and game asset creation. Prototyping, pipeline optimization.

- Game design, game & level editor development, project lead, graphics and user interface design of TWINIWT, the innovative, free to play symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured on both AppStore and Play Store.
- Project management & development of 1FPS GAME SERIES. 4 mobile F2P games: 1FPS: INVADERS, 1FPS: VACUUM, 1FPS: FASTFOOD, 1FPS: GRAFFITI[WIP]
- Cocos2d-x based in-house cross-platform game framework.
- Design, development and artwork of WRECKJUMPER[WIP], forced-perspective sci-fi TBS with dynamic puzzle elements.
- Visualization module for an architectural research project (for evolutionary-algoritm driven facade generation) at ITU.
- Development of Fossicker, open source asset prospector.
- Guest lecturer for M.Arch., M.Sc. in Design Computing courses and B.Arch. design studios at ITU.

EKSERIYA STUDIOS

Aug 2013 - Jan 2015

Graphics Department Lead & TD

Graphics technology and workflow decisions. Tools & pipeline development. Prototyping. Asset shading, lighting.

- · Asset pipeline automation system (import, lighting, rendering, compositing & atlas) for mobile RTS, SILICON WARS.
- Environment art and map editor for RIOT DEFENSE game.
- Pseudo 3D graphics R&D for FOOTBALL WIZARD game.

FREELANCE

JUN 2011 - FEB 2014

Visualization Artist

İSTANBUL

Architectural and product visualization for various firms.

EFOR EVENTS & SIMMETRICO

AUG 2011 - SEP 2011

Assistant Site Manager

Construction site management of the steel structure built for a VIP event.

EFOR EVENTS

JUL 2010 - APR 2013

Event Supervisor

İSTANBUL

Workflow & stage manager for major events. Clients include: Microsoft, TeliaSonera, Huawei, Volvo.

Aşçıoğlu İnşaat

SEP 2009 - Nov 2009

Assistant Site Manager, Internship

İSTANBUL

Application supervision at construction of hospital building of Selenium Twins complex.

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS

</> C / C++ </> 00000 **Python** </> Common Lisp, Scheme 00000 </> x86 Assembly </> **LLVM 1111** 0000 </> UNIX / Shell 00000 </> TeX / LATeX Systems </> Lua, HTML5

DEVELOPMENT TOOLS & LIBRARIES

99999 ⟨/⟩ 🎓 **Emacs** </> **Visual Studio** </> < GCC, Clang, MSBuild 0000 </>> GDB, LLDB 00000 </> Make, CMake </> Git Version Control System 00000 99999 </> Doxygen, Org-Mode </> Xcode, Android Studio

GRAPHICS & VFX SOFTWARE

00000 </>> Blender 3D USD 00000 </> </> GIMP, Inkscape, ImageMagick 00000 </> AutoCAD, DraftSight 999 </> Houdini </> Maya

OPERATING SYSTEMS

</>> **GNU/Linux** 00000 00000 </> Windows 0000 </> macOS

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

NOP Mode

A code annotation and navigation system, designed to be supported by IDE and editor plugins. Aims to improve code navigation for reading code.

2017 Twiniwt Mobile Game, 6x13 Games

An innovative symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured on the AppStore Puzzle and Board categories, as well as Play Store Indie Highlights and Indie Corner. It works on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Written in C/C++, using Cocos2d-x.

2016 1FPS Retro Game Series, 6x13 Games 4 games that work on all popular mobile and desktop

platforms. Written in C++, using Cocos2d-x.

2015 Fossicker, The Asset Prospector, 6x13 Games An asset generator that regexp over asset name to create relevant dummies. Powerful plugin system relies on CLOS and Context Oriented Programming.

Riot Game Map Editor, Ekseriya 2014

Map editor, importer/exporter that lets users both define and tile assets on a grid, export & raytrace the scene. Uses Blender Game Engine and Python.

Sprite Automation System, Ekseriya 2013 A system for automated game asset creation workflow. Uses Python, Blender3D (BPY) and Bash.

2012

Common Lisp parser/reader and writer for IESNA LM-63 Photometry Standard files.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Walking, Computer Science, Technology HOBBIES

Blogging, Literature, Charcoal Drawing

Free / Libre & Open Source Software, COMMUNITIES

Blender Network, Lisp Game Development

